Register of the Thomas T. C. Gregory Papers, 1918-1932
Hoover Institution Archives
Thomas T. C. Gregory Papers,
1918-1932
72059
Gregory, Thomas T. C., 1878-1933
3 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes, 1 oversize box (2.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to the work of the American Relief Administration in Central Europe, the fall of the 1919 Bela Kun communist regime in Hungary, and the 1928 Presidential campaign of Herbert Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Kun, Bela, 1886-1939.; American Relief Administration.; International relief.; Presidents--United States--Election--1928.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Hungary.; Hungary--History--Revolution, 1918-1919.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.
Biographical Note
1878, October 4 Born, Suisun, California
1899 A.B., Stanford University
1918-1919 Captain, 144th Field Artillery, American Expeditionary Force
1919 Director, American Relief Administration, Central Europe, and Assistant Director of Relief of Supreme Economic Council
1919-1933 Trustee, Stanford University
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1932
  - Angell, Frank (Box 1)
  - Baker, George B.
  - Barry, Robert
  - Brown, Philip
  - Causey, William B.
  - Coolidge, Archibld C.
  - Craven, Rear Admiral Thomas T.
  - De Sereys, Comte G.
  - Donovan, William J.
  - Ely, Robert E.
  - Gibson, Hugh
  - Gregory, Admiral Luther K.
  - Gruenberger, H. Alfred
  - Heath, Ferry
  - Hoover, Herbert C.
  - Howard, Roy W.
  - Hunt, William H.
  - Jahncke, Ernest L.
  - Karoli, Catherine
  - Logan, James A., Jr.
  - Nikolic, Baroness Vera
  - Oliver, G. R.
  - Pritchett, Henry S.
  - Schuller, Richard
  - Taylor, Dr. Alonzo
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman
  - General, A-Z
  - Family
- WRITINGS AND SPEECHES
  - "Stemming the Red Tide, A Sketch of the Activities of Herbert Hoover and His Band of Americans in Central Europe Following the Great War," 1919. Typescript manuscript. 84 pages (Box 1)
  - Communism in Central Europe, 1919-1920
  - Economic recovery in Central Europe, 1919
  - Miscellaneous
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1932
  - American Relief Administration, Central Europe
    - Appointment and assignments (Box 2)
    - Austrian relief reports and memoranda
    - Czechoslovakian, Dalmatian, and Hungarian relief reports and memoranda
    - Hungarian political situation
      - Dossier of American Relief Administration, Supreme Economic Council, and other reports and memoranda, including reports on the fall of the Bela Kun government
      - Statement of Michael Karolyi
    - Russian relief reports
    - Telegraphic communications with other American relief offices
      - Typed transcript, June 24 -August 18, 1919
      - Typed and holograph originals
        - April 24 -August 4, 1919
        - August 5 -August 18, 1919 (Box 3)
    - Selected news reports from European newspapers, January 2 -January 23, 1919
    - Travel memorandum of W. B. Causey, December 20, 1918 -July 26, 1919
    - Letters of introduction for T. T. C. Gregory
    - Letters of thanks from Central European governments
  - Coolidge, Calvin. Address before the Union League of Philadelphia, November 17, 1927
  - Hoover for President, 1920-1928
  - Potash concessions in Spain, Solvay Mining Co., case, 1919
  - Prohibition
  - Stanford University
- MISCELLANY
  - Biological material and genealogy (Box 3)
  - Clippings
  - Calling cards
  - Passport, 1919
  - Military discharge, 1919